I just I'm just gonna say you know like
when someone gets a bounty and LS the
sound that is on you should put that in
your tool when something comes up maybe
it'll motivate you oh you
[Music]
[Applause]
did
hey guys real quick I just wanted to do
a shout out to the hacker content team
uh they've been doing an awesome job
with us recently helping with the social
media management side and uh sort of
taking the load off of me so I can focus
on delivering awesome content for you
guys um so if you think your
organization as well could benefit from
some hacker oriented social media
management help then hacker content is
the number one place to get it um and I
highly recommend them so head over to
hacker content.com to send in an inquiry
uh and if you mention the podcast when
you do you'll get your first month of
social media management stuff free um so
yeah check that out all right back to
the Pod you know I'm not even sure we
should say this on the podcast but the
link that I sent you to actually get
into this is the exact same link as the
last one so there's some sort of off
mechanism problem that's happening here
with uh guests getting into the
studio seems to be yeah that's weird man
we got to figure that out um all right
well uh that aside welcome to the
podcast Jrock it's good to have you on
here man thanks for having me man yeah
of course of course and and the um just
us us this week Joel is uh moving across
the country so uh it'll just be me and
you and the sort of impetus for this
podcast uh is I don't know man you you
send me cool stuff from time to time and
uh I appreciate that you you know you
listen to the Pod and you comment on
stuff and you add stuff and you also be
like hey I've got this situation you
know collab on it so I appreciate that
and um the other day you sent me this
really cool uh bug that you ended up
being able to exploit uh relevant to
some of the content we had on the Pod
before and I was like dude you gotta you
got to talk about this on the Pod um so
let's do this man um definitely need to
do an introduction to Jrock and that
sort of thing but let's let's let's give
the let's give the listener a little a
little taste of what's to come with uh
this this metat tag plus d purify bug so
I'll let I'll let you give a a summary
of that bad boy sounds good so um I was
testing an app um where I had found an
HML injection um in many places but uh
the latest version of D purify was used
so getting xss required me to pretty
much focus on dumper only and get a zero
day on there and I figured that it
wasn't really worth the time uh so I
looked at um I started looking at the O
flow and noticed that there was a a path
traversal in the redirect UI parameter
so it allowed me to uh redirect the code
back to any page that I wanted on the
web app um so I tried redirect
redirecting it to the page where I had
ini objection and it worked so um I was
like I can reduct the code to my
objection uh where I had the pick I mean
where the the objection is located at um
so I I was thinking of ways to um leak
the URL so I could steal the code right
um so started off by just testing like
with image tags I mean it worked I could
put in any image on there except that um
because of the default refer policy um
it would not leak the F to me it would
only leak the origin so like the domain
or subdomain so annoying so that did not
work yeah it used to work in the past
right you could just put it that way and
we could leak data but that's not the
case anymore miss the good old days
doesn't it like can can you like I don't
know nowadays I've just become so used
to that you know default refer policy uh
you know was it cross origin strict or
something like that now where it's like
okay that isn't even a thing but like
man back in the day we had it good when
we could just leak anything from the URL
by just getting an HTML injection that's
that that was sick exactly yeah so I
thought of like trying to see if I could
change the refer policy itself so I
looked at mgn docs uh because I wasn't
really familiar with that I mean I knew
what it was but I did not know like if
it was possible to change it with like a
header or something or or by my
injection and turns out that we can uh
with a meta tag uh we can set the meta
tag um and I mean we can set the refer
policy through the meta tag and we can
set it to unsafe URL where it'll send
the whole URL in the refer header if I
had to T that though right I thought so
um well actually first I would I did not
know if it would have worked because the
meta tag was not the head of the page
but turns out it does work do work it
does work um but like you said I thought
the Peri would have caught that and
turns out that it did except that for it
did actually strips it out from the dawn
itself so when I refresh the page
um I can see the refer policy is set to
unsafe yourl but the metat is nowhere to
be found in the D like Dum perice seems
to do its job but for some reason Chrome
still sets the refer policy to
UNL so with all of that said I was able
to leak the uh oath code with anml
dection using um like an image tag so I
can send the ARL to my to myself and
along with the meta tag that is gone but
still sets the refer policy to UNL um so
with both of these I can leak theol code
and get an account to go dang dude that
is lit and and this is still like a a
actively like this can be exploited
right yes uh so I was discussing it with
the program itself and uh turns out that
well we found the the GitHub issue on on
Dum pery uh they said that it's like a a
chrome issue and by looking at Chrome
and the chromium bugs we found that it's
not fixed it's sld out there so this can
still be exploited my favorite type of
issue
man give you a little a little golf clap
here that's that's clutch you know a lot
of times we get people coming on the Pod
being like look at this crazy thing that
I found you know it's fixed now but you
know cool story and and there's lots to
benefit from that but um but you know
this this one's actually still active
and that's that's the best kind and and
I was kind of clicking into this um I
was kind of clicking into this uh sort
of GitHub link that you that you gave me
before so on Don purify they're like
interesting thanks for the heads up
seems like it's a chrome issue and then
you like you said you know you click
over to the Chrome one and I thought
this was hilarious like first they they
like this issue is kind of old from like
2020 so they like have migrated um you
know issue trackers since then so it's
like right go to this issue tracker go
to this issue tractor and then at the
bottom of it it says um David Von cleave
is no longer working at Google uh and so
this is you know issues up for grabs and
then that was like 2021 so it's been
like three years the issue has never
been touched and I feel like this is
massive dude like this this has really
massive impact because I what it seems
to me is like without that meta tag even
being added to the Dom maybe just that
meta tag being created as a as like a
tag object in
JavaScript that meta or that re um refer
policy is being applied to the page
which is kind of nuts MH yeah that's
crazy and um so like I've been looking
at other targets where um I saw that D
per I was used and see if I can uh abuse
that somehow because I'm sure it's
pretty common in in many places right
yeah yeah 100% and and and I I see you
know I'm looking now at this issue I
just sent it to you on on on Discord as
well and uh if you if okay so I I Mis WR
it I was cuz the we we link the the the
GitHub issue in the in the um comment
section or the the description section
but you can even see up at the top it
says uh under headers General in the in
the um Dev tools console says on the top
picture it says referal policy strict
origin when cross origin and on the one
at the bottom after they've done the
HTML injection it says no refer so
that's that's that's pretty weird man uh
that that this is actually allowed and
uh it definitely this is a good trick to
get us back to the good old day days of
like of being able to leak leak data
through the um the
referer yeah I was I actually had never
found something like that because it's
not something I used to look at um but I
was like really I really wanted to steal
the O code just because I I've been
looking at o over the past couple of
weeks or months and um so I focus on
that HML objection tried to see what I
could do with it and started looking at
at the for policy and ended up with
metatag and luckily for enough Trump
hasn't fixed their stuff yet so it works
made it happen man made it happen all
right so so that that's that's the
that's a little little taste of Jrock
and jrock's work um but one of the cool
things about about um about you Jasmine
is that uh you're not not just a a bug
Bounty Hunter you're also like a pretty
like high level security guy as well
which and I kind of talked about this on
a podcast with with Jason hadex a while
back but like I feel like there's
multiple routes for me in the future you
know when I'm kind of thinking about my
future I I feel like I could go the I
could go like the ceso route or like the
you know head of information security
route or whatever could go the corporate
route there I could go the
entrepreneurial route um I could go the
you
know government hacker route um or I
could I could I could you know stay
doing Pok Bounty forever which is
probably what I'm going to do not gonna
lie but um if I were to go the the um
you know SE sish route I would want to
be like you because you have uh while
still being a top a Top Dog in in a uh
in an organization from the security
perspective you're also very very
technical and doing book bounty on a
regular basis and in the weeds um and
you're also a model I understand is that
is that is that accurate yeah no I would
say a model but uh um yeah I guess I was
approached to do uh the cover of a front
page of a of a night or security or
computer magazine oh my gosh dude which
which I did I found it really cool so I
did it yeah not not just my role model
you're a model a model yeah that's great
dude so we we'll we'll put the picture
up on the screen but um I'm not gonna
lie man it's pretty good like like that
is a that is a pretty I mean that's
about as good as you could ever hope for
them to you know have the results come
out so yeah well shout out to the hacker
photographer that picture was taken in
Austin a couple years ago no way really
yeah yeah wow at the one of their L
chees and uh I asked H if you could use
that picture so yeah go go ahead so uh
sent it over and the result is uh is is
pretty cool I actually have a few copies
um here in my place you got to send me
one of those I'll put it up on my wall
yeah all right man so I've told you
enough let's uh let's swing back around
to the to the origin story how did you
how did you get in into Security in
general and how did you get into bug
Bounty um so I actually actually don't
have like a typical background as many
people who do who do bug Bounty um I
started After High School um a program
in U in accounting because I used to be
good at math uh but after he was like H
this not for me so I stopped um and just
like worked a student job for for a year
and then uh one day on my way back home
I saw
um a poster where it said like uh I mean
on my way back home in the Metro or sub
whatever how you guys call it uh of a
poster of was cool um that started a new
um I guess computer science program and
I wasn't really like into computers uh
my whole life like as a kid teenager it
wasn't my thing um and then at that time
when I was 18 I was like I know there's
are plenty of jobs in that space let me
give it a shot and turns out um I really
loved it um so I let you know I did not
love it because my first course ever in
that program was
C and I hated it I barely passed yeah
I'm not sure why I just started with
with C like you should have started with
the basics like I didn't I didn't even
know back then like what a CPU was and
they want me to goe and see I know dude
that's nuts wow so uh yeah so I ended up
like passing the course like making that
uh the project at the end where I had to
create like a like a Tetris or snake
game I forgot what it was so I did it
but barely passed and I actually like
consulted with the um uh with these cool
I guess directors whatnot um because I
said I told them like it's not my thing
like do you have any other like options
like oh yeah we have like networking and
security was like let me try that uh so
in those classes I learned all of like
TCP IP all the OSI layers and all that
stuff uh firewalls VPN and mostly like
networking like Linux um server stuff
like that I did not do any programming
at all in that in those classes um but
it was something that I liked a lot and
I got really good at it uh so after I
was done with that with school um
started working as a CIS admin so
working with um networking like Cisco
routers and switches um like typical s
work AC directory power and like that um
but after a couple years started to get
bored um so I started looking into um
pentesting because at school we had a
few classes on security welcome to the
dark side yeah so we had a few classes
on security um but like it was really
like the basics like they told us what a
firewall was what a wa was what an IPS
IDs antivirus all that stuff um and I
knew that we I could hack as a job um I
was like just it sounds sound it sounds
like illegal but if it's a job it must
be legal right right um so I looked it
up a bit and saw that it was like a a
regular job that people had um so I
started see what I needed to do to get a
job as a pester so I decided to do the
OSP
certification U and keep in mind uh
since I started school in 18 I only
started getting to hacking was like 25
wow um which is like not common in the
bug mon space because I think you start
do pcking with your like in your te yeah
a lot of us have started really early
but there have been some really amazing
people in the community that that have
you know done what what you've done as
well or even later and just kind of come
into it and then just you know absorbed
all the information and and you know
have amazing results so either way works
out but this is definitely I think
probably not the typical route it is
yeah true so uh yeah so back in 2016 I
completed the wcp um and it's funny
because I actually uh did an interview
for a cyber security company Montreal
and did they not it was like in January
February and they didn't take me because
they thought that I was like too far
back so for me to get up to date and
terms of training would have caus them
too much so like you know what this is
like the game changer like I'm gonna get
I'm really motivated now I want to get
it done and then in April I finished USP
in like two which is I think pretty good
because I think the common I think time
frame is like three months where people
do SCP and a lot of a lot of times they
don't pass in the first attempt and I
did within 60 days you passed in the
first
attempt yep dang it Jrock you know I I I
failed the first attempt I I went
through it and I I um yeah you know I I
was five points shy for the for the
first attempt which was so sad and I and
I I didn't make any progress the last
five hours uh it was like it was
heartbreaking um and uh and I didn't do
the lab write up either right because I
was like oh you know I'll pass it right
or whatever but you get bonus points for
doing the lab write up so if I had done
the lab write up then I could have I
could have passed but um yeah it sucks I
I'm curious your thought I mean
obviously you went that route with the
certifications and stuff like that um
you know the the I hear two major sort
of groups of people in insecurity some
people are like ah you know training
courses certifications blahy blahy blah
it's not you know all of it's fake or
whatever but the other and then the
other group is like certifications
classes these sort of things they really
add value and I think it largely depends
on the person you know it largely
depends on like what your learning style
is and whether you're able to sit down
and do structured learning and that sort
of thing but I'm I'm curious your take
on your your academic experience you
know doing some some cyber security
courses and then all versus your
certification and versus self
self-taught and where you're getting the
most bang for your buck out of those
three definitely self thought um so like
for example with OSP um it's as you know
like a lot a lot of self-taught what you
need to do your own research you need to
look look things up learn how things
work but now like I reflect back to when
I did it I realized that thep is like
really just the basics you the basics
nothing nothing more especially
everything that's web app related like
you like you still have like remote
filing inclusions in OSP like nowadays
you never see that right and it's like
really like basic stuff um and uh yeah
like I think for me personally um I
learned better um by like myself like
self-taught and actually like me
watching a course or a class doesn't
work for for like WP you know we have
like um videos of of things I did not
watch a single one I I was better better
while reading the book um Googling stuff
um and so same thing today I have hard
time learning while watching someone
talk um I just I'm just really better at
learning and uh by reading yeah I I feel
like there's multiple I feel like I read
somewhere that there's like visual
Learners auditory Learners and like
kinesthetic Learners right I don't
remember like the actual term for it but
it's like there's some people that need
to just get their hands on it and
there's some people if they read it you
know it'll be good there's some people
if you see it and it'll be good um you
know so I guess it it highly depends on
the person um but I have to say you know
especially in an industry like bug
Bounty or offensive Security in general
where there's so much tinkering required
where where you've got to sit down there
and you got to like fiddle with this and
like move this part around and you know
adjust and that sort of thing I think
the people that learn by having their
hands on something really have a benefit
you know metaphorically of course
because you can't put your hands on it
but like you know like like playing
around with it and and fiddling with it
um I I think that's a big advantage and
I think that's a trend we do see across
a lot of the successful Hunters is that
ability to learn from having your hands
on it and uh and kind of grow from that
that
regard exactly yeah definitely and for
me personally um like as you know in OSP
there's not much of web in yeah in the
course itself uh so I actually learn all
of my web app hacking with the um web
application hackers handbook oh really
nice I read it I read it twice all 900
900 Pages it's long it is long it's long
but this is how I learned uh the most I
just read through it um started
tinkering around and in like some
websites um I remember back then I was
uh looking at Tesla I think on bu crowd
um this is like back in
2017 um and my first year that I did
bugy well I wouldn't say I did bugy but
like um after I did actually got a job
as a pester by the way so this helped me
Le the job uh this was like in February
2017 um and in that month I also got my
first ever bouny for Microsoft hey
nice but uh since I was just knew I had
I did not find another bug or not I did
not get another Bounty for the next six
months o um and Ed up like my first year
doing like 5K were you hunting on a
regular basis though not really I was
still like in a learning phas when I was
reading books I read Peter Yi's book as
well to get like real life example yeah
101 yeah that's that's what it's called
freaking freaking Pete man like I love
that book and I'll tell you dude I when
I read that book I I don't know whether
I don't know maybe I just didn't notice
it at all but um I I read through the
whole book I loved the book I was like
this is the best book ever anyway my
wife you know she doesn't do any any
computer stuff but she was looking at it
and one day and she was kind of just
reading through it a little bit and she
noticed a bunch of like like grammar
errors and stuff like that in the book
and she's like Justin how like what is
going on with this and I'm like I I
don't know like and and maybe I had like
some sort of beta copy or something like
that but I I like to think that I was
just so intrigued by the content that I
just skipped over all of that because
you know the the way he breaks down the
analysis of the activity reports that's
exactly what you got to do for all of
the activity reports when you're exactly
yeah when you're getting started I mean
I imagine you learn from that as well
definitely uh I spent a lot of time in
just reading reports and high activity
um I remember like daily looking at like
let's say let me look at exist today
yeah so looked at as many excess reports
I could see in the in in activity and
yeah this is how I learned pretty much
my my skills that I have today is is
through just reading so let me ask this
then did you do buck bounty before you
got the pentester job at all because you
said the same date or the same month you
got it youth yeah uh so not really so I
started like b m roughly after um I got
the job so I had a colleague that that
did it a bit he was like oh you should
try it so I was like okay I'll give it a
shot um and tried it and my first
attempt worked luckily with with
Microsoft yeah but then like I said the
next six months it did not uh work out
pretty well but I was still learning a
pretty a junior pentester so I was
learning all pentesting I had colleagues
who helped me out and and with time uh I
guess I I gain that's good yeah I feel
like that's also a little bit like for
Me Maybe maybe that's my my opinion but
my my sort of Journey was a little bit a
little bit different than that which
which was I was trying to get the job I
didn't have the osgp right and I wanted
them to pay for the OSP for me you know
to get the ocp um so I was trying to get
these jobs beforehand and the way that I
might in with that was bug Bounty so I
did some bug Bounty beforehand and I was
like hey you know I found all these bugs
I've got you know a thousand rep on
hacker one made x amount of money off of
bug Bounty and uh sorry something's
floating in the screen I just all of a
sudden just grabbed the screen um uh but
and that was kind of my way in was like
Hey I've already got all the skills you
can put me to work on a web app right
away here's the proof um and you also
did that a little bit uh the other way
around getting paying for your own ocp
getting put into the company and then
starting to learn pug Bounty and and
then and then did you continue doing it
while you were as a
pentester um uh yeah and were you
working on network pen testing at the
time or you doing web
stuff uh mostly web stuff um that
helps yeah uh because I didn't actually
I did not want to do networking stuff um
I really like web app even though I was
at it is just I had a passion for it I
found it so interesting that you could
get access to a file on the server TR
the we I was like how is this possible
like what's going on and I think that
Curiosity I think helped me in terms of
learning what up because I really wanted
to know how it worked um yeah no
absolutely that's huge I mean it's the
biggest service exposed in a lot of
thing you know if you just look at it
from a networking perspective I did a
lot of networking contesting when I was
um at my pentesting consultancy but uh
you know you do the port scans you
figure out okay what services can I
interact with and 99.9% of the time if
there's a HTTP service you know HTP
based service exposed that's going to
have the biggest attack surface you know
as compared to other other services so
it definitely makes sense to to focus on
it just from a networking uh Network
hacking perspective as well true yeah
true so so then you worked there you
built your your web hacking skills and
how did you you know turn into the bug
Bounty Beast that you are
nowadays um I think I so at that job
actually uh we used one technology in
particular so I since I was looking at
it almost on a daily basis uh found a
few tips and tricks I played that the
bug Bounty it worked nice um and I think
in the
end just gaining experience and like I
think what I learned while doing pet
testing I applied to bug bouny and what
I learned to bug b appli to pet testing
and doing both at the same time um
helped me a lot and to build that
reputation like I think while I was
pretty active back in like 20
2019 um while still doing b as a hobby
and not not fulltime I had made my way
like in the top 40 uh on bu gr I was
most active bu that that time um but in
2019 is also the Year my son was born so
my activity
went way down since things got a little
complicated yeah a bit more uh so back
then I could pretty much do like all
nighters of pcking I remember like going
to bed at 5 waking up at 8 being in the
office at 9ine and being like like
really would fine with that but not no
dude you're not one of those people that
need to sleep three hours a night are
you uh I can't my gosh sleep like three
four hours night and that's
ridiculous uh but now like just last
night I I was on something uh stayed up
until like two so submitted my report I
went to bed at 2:30 wake up at 8 and
like I'm tired but I'm still like I can
go through the day totally fine wow I
know it's not healthy um so like I try
to sleep as much as I can still so like
I might take a nap later this afternoon
um but yeah I yeah I can do that wow
dude that I'm jealous I if I don't get
at least seven hours of sleep then I'm
I'm feeling it so I'm like trying to get
back my I was kind of staying up late
for a little while and now I'm trying to
get back to like waking up at 6 so I'm
I'm the past couple days I've been like
you know feeling great in the morning
getting up getting my workout in you
know hitting the hot tub with the coffee
you know it's great and then it get
started with the day but then it's like
you know at 4 or 5 I'm
like um so I I I am jealous I have to
say um so so okay you've been doing
you've been doing pen testing now did
you ever do a s as a full-time bug
Bounty
Hunter uh roughly um like six months
where I where I did like B mon full time
and also was like a
consultant um there was like four four
years after my first pester job uh at
the same company uh so I decided to give
it a scent for like six months uh my son
was roughly six months as well um when I
decided to to do that um but I did not
it's not for for me I realized after
those six months that I can't do this
full time because when I wake up in the
morning I don't feel the motivation to
hack um for me was like mostly maybe
just because I was exhausted of doing
that fulltime for like the past four or
five years where I was constantly
hacking day and night because my it was
pesting 40 hours a week hacking on
evenings um two three times a week Plus
on weekends once in a while so I
probably did like six hours of hacking
for the past couple
so when I did it full time I was like
let me just relax a bit um so I barely
did any hacking on those six months no
yeah so I actually built up a um my own
Recon tool in that time frame uh which I
don't use anymore that's another thing
dude like I feel like I often I guess
I've been doing full-time B Bounty for
for four years now it's like I feel like
for me programming was a bit of a Escape
that didn't pay good dividends for me I
it did for a little while but like often
times I'm like you know be because bug
Bounty is so untangle like you know sure
you can have gadgets and stuff like that
or like maybe you'll get a v here there
but like if you don't H submit a
report you're not really feeling very
accomplished and you don't know for sure
that you can go and do something right
like you know you don't know for sure
that today if I sit down at the desk I'm
going to find a bug and I'm going to
make you know $5,000 or whatever right
so instead you say oh well but I know
for sure that I can write a script to
scan these ports and put it in a
database today right so I'm like that's
something that I know I can do so I've
got the thing I know I can do versus the
thing that I'm not sure that I can
actually do and it becomes very
attractive to do the thing that you know
you can succeed in and feel like you
progress in right but but it kind of
takes you away from the thing that's
actually generating Revenue a lot of the
time is that did you s generate or did
you experience something
similar yeah and I think others have
mentioned in the in the PO as well where
the cost of maintaining the tool itself
was greater than the um the investment
that you were putting in um so like for
me yes I was able to like get a database
of everything that I wanted
but I will still Mount first on some low
hang food Recon related bugs because
there are people
have like crezy automation I did not I
only wanted like half data for example
um let's say there's a zero day on on I
don't know Confluence if I know I have
like a Pages where I can find Confluence
on my database I can maybe go to it and
I report it if they said prod um but I
found that it I was not always first and
for the time that I was it wasn't really
worth it worth my time looking into it
um so decided to just like do what I
love and which is just using burp
repeater
and manual haing yeah man and if I do
need Rec well there's today's new magly
plenty of people who have data that I
need so I could just collaborate with
those guys exactly and it's pretty low
cost too you know like like I mean
depending on the amount of involvement
from the person I I've done splits of
25% to you know 50% and and it's like
okay well you know if you're if you're
providing the PC they're providing the
data you know it's like a match made in
heaven there um so it's good it's good
that we have friends like that that will
you know it's kind of like uh vul vul is
a service there right you know I just
thinking about that yeah exactly it's
good because like you said there's cost
you know there's cost to just running
the infrastructure itself you know just
you know whatever $100 a month or $200 a
month or whatever but then there's also
like the opportunity cost of how much
time have I spent coding this tool
versus how how much money could have
made you know hacking and especially
when you're good enough to do bug bounty
on a regular basis and you know that
cost is pretty high um and and thinking
about it in terms of opportunity cost is
is pretty tricky um the flip side of
that for me as a full-time Hunter is
it's very hard for me to take time off
um because I don't have
any you know I'm not taking paid time
off right I'm taking unpaid time off by
by nature of exct the the you know
career path um and so it's like it would
be nice to have that automation running
and you know hear a ding from time to
time being like Oh Bo boom that sort of
thing I do miss that from my Recon
experience you should I mean do you
still have a Recon or you don't I mean
it's you know like like it's there it's
written in Python 2.7 uh you know but it
it doesn't it's not running anymore
actively um so nly is my Recon tool
now
I just I'm just going to say you know
like when someone gets a bounty and L
the sound that is on you should put that
in your tool when something motivate you
I did so I I like um I like pavl and
dogged my uh myself and my my
father-in-law too because like like you
know anytime I hear it I'm like you know
the heart rate would go up the the the
slack ping or whatever um and uh and my
father-in-law also I told him you know
hey you know whenever sound happens or
whatever it's uh it's a vul that I found
because this is when I was really
hitting the Route 53 takeovers and it
was like you know they're dropping every
day every other day and so anyway we'd
be hanging out with them and we'd hear
it go off and he would he would be like
w you know he to get up and start doing
a dance it's like yeah um it's pretty
fun you know there's definitely fun
sides of the of the Recon stuff but I
don't know I think for me sitting down
actually dropping some some crits every
once in a while from Good Old sitting
down and doing research which is really
big and then also like like you just
shared right here on the Pod um you find
cool stuff re you know sort of
revolutionary techniques and and uh
Innovative techniques um that you can
share with other people and you can keep
to yourself and and utilize um when
you're actually in the weeds doing the
research um rather than just trying to
be the first one to find a
wellestablished technique yeah and for
me since it's only like as a hobby bante
I don't need the money so I don't live
by I don't need to find bugs I do what I
want to do and for me I have more fun
doing manual hacking than focus on the
Ron only yeah I believe that man I I
that's one of the things that I've been
kind of kind of um you we're going we're
going deep here but uh you know lately
I'm a fulltime B Bounty Hunter and I do
the podcast so I've got like one
standing meeting a week or whatever
right of like you know record the
podcast with Joel on this time or record
the podcast with J rack at this time um
but you know for some reason I I still
have that like and I could take the rest
of the week off no one would be the
wiser right but I still feel that like
anxiety of some sort of like why why am
I not working right now you know or like
even when I am working it's like I don't
know should I be working more it just
doesn't feel as free as I actually am
and I know in my head I'm free like I
could go do whatever I wanted I could go
you know get lunch or whatever so I
think lately what I've been trying to do
is uh I mentioned you know I I talk
about my hot tub time fairly often here
on the Pod but you know it's kind of
like a meditation and prayer time as
well you know go out there enjoy the
nature pray meditate that sort of thing
um but I've been trying to reflect on
that freedom in the mornings and be like
sort of you know Gaslight myself into
into uh into to feeling that freedom
that's actually there but you know is
not as easy to feel sometimes so um yeah
I I I definitely I definitely understand
the draw of traditional employment
though um which which brings us back to
what you're doing now right you you you
you left that full-time bug Bounty and
you went back into the workforce and
where did you
land I landed in a small company
Montreal um I guess in the startup phase
um it wasn't I mean the company had been
founded like in 2009 so for roughly 10
years um 10 year
startup yeah uh so they hired me um to
to be the head of IT security um
okay the CTO yes um they looked at my my
resume they saw that was been testing
for a couple years um back then my bug
Bounty resume was building up as well I
wasn't a model yet but you know my my
name was like you like our names can be
Google and they see what we do and stuff
like that so um and to that went really
well um and then yes so I got hired so I
worked with everything from abset
compliance and like all of the topics
and security physical security as well
uh for that start physical security as
well uh for the office yeah uh and then
a year later we got acquired by NASDAQ
which is where I work now nice nice so
uh yeah so join NASDAQ to an acquisition
and I currently work at NASDAQ uh in
infos as a senior director very cool man
I I'm I'm wondering about that
transition because if I you know I can
say with a high degree of confidence
that I understand a lot about the
offensive security side of of of
security stuff I I understand how to get
in I've done Network pen testing I've
done you know appsec stuff I've done
mobile stuff I've done iot stuff I
haven't done as much Hardware stuff but
you know here and there with Joel and
stuff like that um so I have a diverse
background there but I feel like going
into like a head of I you it security or
in your case sort of head of security
you even doing some some you know
physical stuff at the office um I feel
like that would put me out of my comfort
zone which would which wouldn't be bad
and I feel like I could figure it out
but like how is that
transition uh but you just said the word
it was definitely out of my comfort zone
but I'm the type of guy where I like
challenges so and as soon as I reach out
to me was like man I want this job oh
that's cool uh it's like it's out of a
comfort zone I know there's like great
potential I think this can lead to
something really cool which in the end
it did through the acquisition U but so
like their main goal was to get a sock
to report and I had heard of Saku in the
past since I as a consultant I worked
with it a bit but like I would I never
LED like a company getting to a so to
report uh so learned a lot um on the job
had to do a lots of research on what is
sock to uh
what is ISO t0001 and what is all that
stuff I already with PCI and like that
but we don't use it but getting an idea
of what those Frameworks are and what
they require um same thing for like
standards like nist um all of those I
guess acronyms that are important
compliance world what are they whether
do they whether they require something
like that uh so learned a lot on on that
on for the compliance side of things um
also I guess created our absec our
developing management PR prr um I
already had experience in in doing that
as a pentester where I kind of helped
out in terms of like code reviews um
using SAS last and stuff like that um so
pretty much started the security program
from scratch um this also includes like
um security awareness training program
um making sure that and also another
part of my job was managing it
so yeah I was also the head of it oh my
gosh both umbrellas under me
yeah definitely in a startup then he's
like all right you take any you take
care of all those computer
things so I was alone for a couple of
months and I was the first employee in
it and security no way so I had to build
things up from scratch the only thing
that they had uh this company that did
like uh or still do um ESG I'm not sure
if environmental social governance it's
like um hard to explain um but it's like
something that's is pretty not pretty
common but it's getting pretty common
out there nowadays
um so we did an ESG SAS tool um so
considering SAS um we do well I mean we
hosted on the cloud and so I had to make
sure our Cloud was Secure so um yeah so
when I joined the only security I guess
tool or topic that I had covered was
passwords they had a password manager
for the company that's it so I made sure
that all end points had antiviruses and
literally build up from scratch like
tofa like just get the bases covered I
mean in their defense like that that's I
mean at least they're using a password
manager I mean that that's that will
stop some stuff you know so if if you
had to pick one thing you know that
might be it uh which is which is pretty
cool um I did just Google this ESG thing
I have heard of this this is
environmental social and corporate
governance it says is a set of
considerations including environmental
issues social issues and corporate
governance that can be considered in
investing um exactly gotcha so you guys
were building a SAS tool for
that yep um so a almost a almost a
exactly year after I joined we got
acquired by n wow dude what a n is the
that is that is that is awesome timing
and I yeah and you got in at a at a
pretty good good level too running
running all of the it stuff for
them yeah exactly and I think it's what
deserve my senor director um Ro that
NASDAQ because without me at that
startup uh we would wouldn't have gotten
acquired by NASDAQ wow um so that's sick
dude I think congratulations that's that
is a one boss move right there I have to
say um so yeah quite the jump and uh I
learned a lot um while in that year um
but I'm pretty confident that I did a
good job because I think without help
like I said we got acquir nzac so I
think it's in the end it's I think I did
a good job absolutely that's a big
that's a big dub man um so that's where
you are now senior director at NAS stack
um doing similar things as you were
doing at the startup you know managing a
large security program or um not really
so um since Indiana that startup we were
only two employees in security myself as
the head and I got a an employee as well
um NASDAQ is obviously a lot bigger
right so we have several different teams
in
infosec um and then I work mostly well
not mostly I still work in lots of
different areas because I'm a director
so I need to look at certain stuff so I
do work with like the sales team a while
um marketing absec compliance still um
need to talk to our sock team once in a
while in case something happens threaten
tell like a bit of everything but mostly
on like on a manager type of um task so
I won't do any pen testing sometimes I
do jump in because I want to do it I I
see something I'll take a look so I do
it just for fun uh same thing for like
red team we also do red teaming um and
yeah so a bit of everything you gotta
Flex on the team a little bit too every
once in a while like like like I had I
had a um you know when I was working at
this this uh
um consultancy you know my my boss was
was not in the requests you know at all
pretty much um and then sometimes we'd
have like you know somebody was on PTO
and like we needed to double down on
something and he would like just jump in
and like pop something and I'm like dude
this is lit you know and so I think I
think also you know from time to time we
show the people that you're working with
on a regular basis that even though
you're not you know maybe in the
requests every single day as a part of
your job J that you can still get in
there and do stuff I think that that
does a lot for respect as
well yeah and also since uh I'm seen as
a manager some people don't know my
background so I've had someone telling
me what a
could uh I know what a cookie is like
look look me up a bit just but like yeah
I I've seen people like trying to think
that I'm not technical right and then I
had to explain them like oh by the way I
know what this is like yeah blah blah
blah blah blah so just to get get an
idea of like
um um I don't know like how can I say
this um get an idea of like difference
between manager type position techical
some people think managers are only
managers and don't have medical
background but I think having both
definitely helped in terms of both
managing and doing technical work and
understanding certain risk associated to
it's a it's a it's a big differentiator
I think for you as well um you know it
gives you a lot of job security I know
even in the um you know outside of
management and the sales aspect as well
you know people that actually understand
the technology that they're working with
on a regular basis can do sales well you
know if you have that additional excuse
me if you have that additional little
skill set because it's like um you know
you're actually able to talk to the the
points that people are caring about when
they're thinking about buying a product
so um it's great being technical man I
love being technical uh because it it
applies to so many Realms hey guys real
quick I want to remind you about the
critical thinking Discord Community
there's been a ton of great activity on
the chats lately people just kind of
shooting the breeze to drop in New
hacking tips and advice uh sharing cool
research that sort of thing uh so it's
definitely something you're going to
want to get in on if you haven't already
also we've got the subscriber tiers in
place now which will give you access to
really cool things like Master Class AMA
uh just random scripts that I drop it's
kind of like our Inner Circle um so if
you want to get in on that please do we
would really appreciate it also it helps
support the show so if you're interested
in any of that head over to cb. show/
Discord to join the community today and
we'll see you over there all right back
to the show all right all right so
that's that's the career path once again
I'm gonna just you
know that move uh that you made from
fulltime book bounty to head of it it's
kind of nuts um so that it's great to
see your friends take dubs like that and
uh and thanks for giving me the Hol I've
heard that story in little bits and
pieces obviously seen your face on a on
a cover of a magazine or whatever but um
had had the full story um so speaking of
your your technical capabilities uh
let's let's go back into some of that
stuff and uh talk about some of the cool
cool bugs that you found and topics that
um that you had uh so the one one that
came sort of came to mind that was on my
list and your list um was about this is
about a year ago now you tweeted out it
took 5 years but I finally found my very
first critical ooth related bug last
night I found ACH in the past imp pen
engagements but never on a bug Bounty
program um and so I was like oh well you
know he he he did the oath thing that's
great oath is a is a um a commonly
abused technology I I'd say um and and
it showed up in your list here is you've
been finding a lot of oath related bugs
so can you talk about a little bit about
how you developed that methodology and
maybe talk about some of the quirks of
the bugs you
found um yeah sure so I back back in the
days when I started doing I was mostly
like a server side kind of guy and still
I'm um I focused mostly on on server
side bugs um but with time I think I
gained um an appreciation for what o is
and how complicated it is and how I
would say easy we can find bugs but like
there are so many different anti vors in
it that a lot of times you'll find
something no matter what um and it only
takes like one extra little piece that
you can chain with it for example that
HTML injection with the dump Veri with
metatag since with that part reveral um
I only needed one more thing with and to
leak the URL and so token and a lot of
times is
like it's I wouldn't say easy but I've
been finding a lot so I find that like
people are maybe not looking at it or
because I'm not finding like really
crazy thing apart from one which I was I
actually put it in the list uh which was
like what the is going on here um it's
like just basic stuff like redirect
yourui open redir um open I mean uh
sometimes it allows subdomains so an xss
on a subdomain works as well can still
that o code that way um just like basic
o vulnerabilities nothing like no like
uh crazy technique just regular stuff
you have here in the little in the notes
we we created um you know mentioning
Fran's Dirty Dancing blog post on on a
and I I love that blog post so much we
talk about it on a regular basis here on
the Pod because it's like he he gave a
name to something that was kind of um I
guess unnamed before this whole concept
of like a not happppy path where the
code is not parsed right um you know
because the normal flow for a is you
know you go through the flow or whatever
the code gets redirected back to the
call back and then that code gets
consumed and either tra traded for an
off token or that to token gets used
directly with the API um but if you can
find some way to manipulate that call
back location then that code doesn't get
consumed and then you can use something
like a accss in a subdomain like you
mentioned um to to leak that that code
to the attacker and then the attacker
can provide that that um you know do
that Swap and get the token or use the
token itself for for API calls um so
that that uh you my my my pulse starts
to go up a little bit anytime I see a
you know a a flow where I can control
any part of the redirect flow
essentially where it's not just totally
static and I put friends D dancing
article in there because it is what
helped me really I guess I wouldn't say
master but I guess understand better a
lot because I knew what it was I knew
how we could find Rel with it but I did
not know like certain things that he
mentions in that blog post that I now
understand yeah um and for me like every
time I look at a I just open the tab
just in case I need to go back to it and
I don't get ideas on on certain things
that I maybe haven't looked at um so
shout out to him like this is a a really
excellent um and blog post not sh like
than as well because it has led to a
couple of bugs of mine just by reading
his blog absolutely man yeah FR is fr is
always coming up with crazy stuff like
this and and you also have here you know
reading the art of see that is one of
the things that I actually haven't done
for aath yet I need to go down and and
and you know check it out do you know
how how chunky it
is um well there is like a the a orc but
there's also one uh that's like the
security best practices oh really which
is where I looked at the most because it
says like it shows like all attack
vectors uh on a uh well not all but I I
guess most that they have um thought of
um so I've looked at that quite a bit
this one hold I'm GNA send it to you in
the chat is it RFC
6819 it's ooth 2 threat model and
security
considerations uh let me look at the
nope I don't think it is I'm gonna I'm
gonna link this this one as well because
these dude man I wish I wish more uh and
you know I suppose we should probably
just read the whole thing anyway because
it's like you know I'm sure there are
security consideration that a lot of um
you know that the RFC writers hadn't
really written um uh oh look at that
oath 2 security best
practices this is what I read very nice
dude so this is not a specific RFC this
is a um no you're right it's a it's a
draft associated with it that's that's
cool that's really good I'm going to go
ahead and Link this down in the
description I've never seen this before
I'm going to go ahead and read this
afterwards um but yeah this seems like
there would be some great takeaways in
here yeah definitely um so it shows like
the best practices but us as as
attackers we can see if those are
applied or not so definitely helps in
terms of fighting
bugs um so yeah I'm pulling a Joel here
and I'm getting nerd sniped in the
middle of a pod like starting to read
this I was like wow I actually haven't
seen a lot of the attacks that are kind
of mentioned in
here very cool I agree and one of I'm
not sure if actually so recently I found
the bug uh which I put in the dog but uh
not sure if I can just talk about it now
uh because yeah it's not mentioned um so
I found a weird race condition bug
recently uh so you know the all out flow
once once you're logged in I mean you're
logged in but after a while you need to
refresh the
token uh
so I accidentally noticed that I could
send uh the call that refresh the token
I could send it without the refresh
token and just the client ID and still
get access to an access token that's
weird so just using the cookies
associated with it no no cookies no
authentication at all yeah but it only
worked while a user was getting logged
in so what I did was just send requests
constantly to the endpoint without
authentication without a refresh token
to get an access token and when the user
logs in eventually it's spits out an
access token that I can use until this
next token expires yep any user what the
heck dude that's the weirdest thing ever
what is the what does the server
side what does what what does the server
side code for that even look like like
they they explained it to me uh I would
have to read it through uh that's nuts
but this yeah I I've never seen anything
and dude it's a miracle that no one has
logged into somebody else account on
accident because of that cuz you'd think
that there would be some sort of like
Collision or
something I thought about that as well
like so when I was testing it I was just
like testing the O out flow um and then
like I went in repeater took a request
send it over playing with it remov the
refresh token and it works like huh why
is this working I don't have any cookies
there's no refresh tokening your mind
like you must been like what am I
missing but then but then the issue is
how to rep
so after a while after like a minute or
two it stopped working I like okay this
is weird so I thought maybe maybe it's
during the login so I sent the like
request an intruder um logged in and see
if Intruder I got an access token and I
did get an access token no way I I could
see you just sitting there like how H
how did this you know you you've got the
the tab you know the repeater tab open
in burp or the history and you can see
it giving with no cookies with no IDs
with nothing on the left hand side and
then somehow it's giving you the access
token you're like what the
frick it's funny because I actually
messaged um Sebastian and I was like
guys what do you think is going on here
and I explained was like I don't know a
risk condition and turns out it is a
risk condition but I was like I'm not
sure if it's a risk condition we're not
racing against anything it's just like
ends up getting an access token somehow
just the tokens out there like no one's
bus
that's crazy man wow it just and is this
on a buck buny program or is this on a
pentest uh bu program I actually got
paid out yesterday yeah fixed yesterday
as well so I'm happy they fixed it
talking about it today D that's nuts man
I cannot believe that actually happens
in a bug b any because like you know on
pentest you see all sorts of weird stuff
you know and and it's like weird as
normal on pentest because it's like okay
all these sketchy little apps you know
but like in in on bug bony I like like
to think that people try to do some due
diligence right before they actually MH
start a bug bounding program and you
know essentially bet money on their
security um so the fact that that showed
up in a bug Bounty environment is just
nuts to me yeah very cool though crazy
uh really lucky as well likeed what are
the chances of me just trying that
removing the refresh token and and by
default there were no ofation cookies it
only relied on refresh token to get a a
new access token
so weird dud so so weird yeah that's
that's one of the things too man is like
so much of our job that's one of the
things that's I think is a little bit
unsettling for me as well it's like so
much of our job is luck of sorts you
know just sort of manufacturing your own
luck of sorts just like trying
everything and like trying weird stuff
and then noticing when something weird
happens um and so uh I've had a a really
I've been I've been lucky of getting
luck yeah if I want say that so and back
in the in an L in La couple years
ago U not sure if you consider say
Target or not but I I won't say just in
case
um there was an application um that many
people tested I went through it um
fuzzed a bit so it had like a weird
authentication form like login form and
it just felt like I could probably
bypass that somehow but I did not bypass
it so I moved down
a day
later I started getting emails from like
an internal uh distribution list and
those emails had like
pii um so with my fuzzing somehow I got
added in an DL and was getting like
access request for to to data so those
emails had like um employe full name
phone number address what and they were
requesting access it was like a a access
request one started requesting access to
certain data and I was a recipient of
those access requests I wonder if you
submitted did you submit an access
request form and they're like CC all
access no no because in the email itself
we could see everybody who got the email
and it was all like the company email
and me my Jrock weher one.com Emil that
in that list so I had no idea what
happened uh so yeah this is one issue I
was really like wow man another another
funny story is um I was hacking on on a
big company while back they do uh many
LHS and um I was I I found a few bugs on
the app um but I was kind of stuck and
um I just sent a few xss payloads and a
blind payloads and hope that when they
would pop a year later it pops What and
then around the same time one guy um
messages me on on Twitter and like GI me
[__] like oh you just ruined my day I
was like what hell's oh my gosh what
yeah so obviously um I looked at the my
excess Hunter dashboard first script me
I cared more about that than the the T
right but it had just I was just coming
back from work uh it was on a Friday
evening of course had my laptop yeah so
I was at the moment go was like Hey bab
I one sec I'm just going to sit down at
at the uh the Des here and pull up my
laum and see what's going on
so um I looked that up and um from what
I had understood is that that guy who DM
me on Twitter to give me [__] he um
created a report and complained on my
behavior of putting blindess payload oh
my gosh and that complaint got sent to
um an email system and email system and
it popped on there dude no way so
without his complaint without his
complaint of my fa
I would not have gotten that I think 9k
Bounty that I gotest that's clutch you
you should say message him back on
Twitter being like hey man I just wanted
to let you you made my day like oh I did
I did I was like oh sorry well I'm doing
like ethical testing like here's a
program page like we're allowed to to to
hack so sorry that it ruined your day
for whatever you're doing but like what
I did is completely fine as for the
policy here and was like oh sorry uh I
didn't know like you guys were we doing
and also you just made me 10 grand so
thanks pretty much yeah wow I don't
think it was that much but it was like a
a large five for large that's great man
wow that that's that's a good one I and
I have this on the list too because I
went and watched as I do you know before
these episodes I went and stalked you a
little bit and wa watched some of your
your talks you've given um at activity
con and um some writeups you've done in
other places and it seems like
you I would say you skirt the line a
little bit
when it I used to when it comes to
Social Engineering in Buck Bounty like I
I I saw a write up I think of like you
you saying like I submitted a contact
form with a link in it and then some
admin clicked that link and then that
like one shot rce to Jenkins instance in
the back end or something like that and
so I I'm wondering so one like one you
said you used to so I'm wondering if you
still do that and then the other one is
H how has that been received in you know
if you had to a number to your hit rate
on those like how many times are they
like no that social engineering bad you
know hand slap versus like oh my gosh
you just shelled my CI so I'm gonna give
you a
bounty um it it worked once or twice
that's is one case where it did work uh
through a contact form but I don't
usually do those anymore um because um I
mean it it never pops yeah yeah but one
thing that I do find that it did work
again back in the day before the refer
policy we're talking in the beginning is
that uh sometimes like when you test
ssrf you put in your url um you can be a
we or whatnot u and sometimes it does
get like hyperlink and you can have
admins click on it and when they click
on it um the refer used to be sent to
your to your server and I was able to
disclose a few I guess um sensitive data
with that just being like an admin uh
path that I had not seen uh certain uh
uuid or whatnot and this still works um
I I had a case that happened like this
week um where someone clicked on an
employee clicked on my link on my link
and um with the same program actually
that um the metatag thing so with the on
URL that I had theaction it set it to
multiple pages so when an employee
clicked on my link it sent the refer
header to um to my server so I was able
to link data with that no way
that's clutch but yeah it's most of the
time that it did work was through like a
reer header leak that where it leak
something sensitive wonder you know I
wonder how many of these applications
are using Dom purify under the hood and
and I wonder if we should just start
sort of spamming
metatag uh you know refer unsafe URL
plus you know some sort of image uh you
know tag around to try to harvest these
because image tags are going to get
through Dom purify and and then and then
it'll send a request out and then you'll
get the referer and then you can kind of
you know maybe if there's like a
security by obscurity or something like
or even just knowing in in in internal
paths can be really helpful or you might
get lucky and there's an O token in the
URL so yeah maybe true crazy man I like
that do do you do any other I guess On
The Fringe of uh social engineering
stuff like like like some people will do
like typo squatting or something like
that to trigger you know their payloads
or anything um
um not really um I I did buy a few
domains in the past but it was for a bug
for example a bad reg X or red never
knew what it is but like yeah you found
that in the past for example you
actually mentioned it in tweet I think
like github.com you could do like a
github.com and so I bought some di for
that chain with other bugs um but it's
not like social engineering right sure
um but like if you're talking about
social specifically the only things that
I've done is what you just said in
regards sending a link like draw contact
form where I knew I was confident that
if they clicked on it uh it was going to
work because I had Recon and I knew that
it was reachable through other means and
what not um that's yeah I feel like
that's I feel like that's acceptable
personally I don't know some programs
might get a little bit pissy about you
submitting a uh something through the
contact form but I I feel like that's
that's fair play um uh just one one last
thing about that it actually happened um
in a light hiking event and they had a
necessary Sheriff so in there I
obviously put my my name to identify
myself and it got a hit turns out it's
actually an employee who clicked on my
link so it looked like I hit it but I
did not
oh they did
investigation uh they found out that it
was an employee clicked on my link um so
it wasn't um it wasn't necessar so just
informative yeah it does show that's you
know like how easy it is to get an ssrf
of sorts you know within an organization
when you just send a link to an employee
they click the link and that's you know
depending on if they've got a privileged
um you know position in the network
that's that's an ssrf of sorts um
exactly Yeah It's Tricky man you know
I'm sure you as a um you know head of
security guy you know being a senior
director of security kind of have to
think about these things as well but
like bug Bounty is great for anything
that doesn't affect like social
engineering and stuff like that but man
it's so much easier to get in Via social
engineering than it is to get in by
these application
bugs for sure um yeah just last year or
two years ago um the Vegas event
remember what happened there I do yeah I
freaking do man crazy it's nuts man so I
I think I think there should be
absolutely and this is you know my
native opinion but I think there should
be a lot of resources allocated to
preventing that sort of thing in an
organization because that seems to be
the easiest way to make something happen
definitely yeah um looking at the list
we've got here again um it seems like
you also are an advocate of getting
intimate with the application which is
good yeah and you said that there might
be some stories relating here with
regards to this leading to a a MOAB
which I I assume is a a reference to the
episode with uh with mayonnaise uh the
mother of all bugs tell me a little bit
about that yeah so it's not like a
mother of all bugs but like I found many
issues because of that so I was getting
intimate with the app reading the dogs
and I love it I love it so much
dude I was uh you know getting getting
intimate with the app yeah sorry
continue so yeah I was reading the docs
and um I found that um it did like XML
parsing it literally said like oh we do
XML parsing blah blah blah that but yeah
and um I also realized that in some
cases the docs don't necessarily mention
that it Parts XML it'll just say like
the acur name for example I don't know
let's say XXX ml so there's a market
language a lot of times it it is XML um
and I had found an EXC already U by
reading through docs where it said like
literally said XML pring but in those
other lesser known XML formats um
standards or specs it did not say XML at
all it only said like refer to the spec
on
W3 so I in the dogs I looked for W3 I
found plenty of them oh wow and most of
them were vulnerable Texas wow because
by defile they did not do like uh they
not protect against xsc properly so just
by like analyzing the dogs um seeing how
they write it up they don't always say
XML but they'll say like um we we par
these kind of files um refer to the dog
on W3 so I looked at for W3 like I said
found plenty of them and and they all
led to more more bugs that's definitely
an underestimated I think trick
when you're dealing with applications
because like I often see so many bugs in
parsing of custom file file formats you
know it could be server side bugs could
be client side bugs just the other day A
friend of mine found a bug um I think
we'll probably write this up and put it
up somewhere but um he he had to
download this this software and like
like this proprietary software and we we
were trying to do it without downloading
the proprietary software but this each
one of these files because it's a
proprietary software is signed the by by
a you know RSA key you know and it's
like you can't you can't fiddle with it
at all because we were just going to you
know kind of reverse the binary format
and just elongate a specific field to
put our our payload in there um but but
it was signed so we actually had to like
boot up the software and like inject the
the payload the xss payload in this you
know piece of code and uh or in the like
field in the in the software and then
export the file and then give that file
to like a JS uh um you know file that
was actually doing the signature
validation uh in the browser which is
nuts and um and then it would actually
pop the xss uh and and so like these
custom formats whether they're XML
whether they're you know some binary
level format that sort of thing there's
almost always bugs there and and and so
to your point about reading the docs
though I I'll never forget the first
live hacking event I went to there's
there was 20 minutes left in live
hacking event my um this is actually in
um in was was talking with some people
and comparing notes and somebody was
really close to to finding a bug um or
to passing another person and all they
needed to do was find one bug so like
man how can I find a bug um in the last
couple minutes of this event and so he's
like you know what I'm gonna do I'm
gonna go to the docks and I'm G to
contrl F for
URL is what he did and he went to the
API docs control F for for URL found an
API request that was taking in a URL as
a parameter you know and and just sent
that request off and his Boom full read
ssrf it it dropped in the last 20
minutes of the live hacking event he
probably got it in under five minutes at
the end um and so reading those reading
those docs and searching for things like
W3 or you know XML or URL or that sort
of thing I yeah man that always pays
dividends yeah it does um taking time to
to read and just not only to like find
certain keywords just to read and
understand what is expected on
application how it works and especially
when the app is really complex and many
features sometimes it's just good to
read dogs and get a better idea of what
you're looking at and understand what's
understand what you're doing in the end
nice well we got to wrap this episode
here shortly but you have two cool bugs
here that I can't skip over you've got
arbitrary ATO via graphql and ssti to RC
VI anable expression so where do you
want to go man this is I I'm going to
sit back and get my water bottle and and
listen yeah so let's go with the uh
arbitrary atto
um so let's say the app is simar to
slack where in slack not sure if you
know but you can add like external users
to your slack work space um and they
only have access to specific Channel um
it's not the same thing but the other
was similar where if I as an admin or
let's say you as an admin add me as an
external user to your on
tenant um I will get access only to data
that you give me access sure um turns
out though that the graphql endpoint on
that application did not have um proper
authorization checks so me Asal user I
could U make graph queries I did not
have access to the data but I did access
to the endpoint itself itself I could
run queries but no data was returned um
so I was able to generate taking back
like null or something like that or no
just like data like you know the data
object just just okay but some but for
some mutations it did not work but
queries it did it's pretty common I've
seen this many times so something that I
need to understand here continue you
picked my
interest so I as the attacker AKA
external user to the application I can
um do graph K queries um and then one
query itself where um there was like an
ID related variable I um put like a
single quote and it generated a nice
verbos um error message in the response
and in the error message in response it
did have um an internal JWT which uh the
scope was assigned to um sis admin ah
you love to see uh it yeah and it also
leaked two headers uh one was related to
the customer ID for example um it was my
tenants ID which this is like a public
ID to my own tenants just I'm
authenticated but without
authentification you can't get those
IDs
um in a way uh and also the current user
ID which was the um the admin of the
application dude uh which was like the
let's say you so uh it took me so I
reported that blog as it because I felt
like um the token is leak as as admin or
super admin I'll let you guys like
investigate it down want abuse it so
reported it um ended up self closing um
because the impact wasn't shown so I was
like okay I'll I'll think about it and
read the docs uh read the AP API docs I
forgot about it three months go by I was
like oh [__] let me look at this again
uh tested it again it works but like
okay need to now I need to fine like and
it's showing back so um right through
the docks found a way to um I mean found
the API card that it needs to do to make
that token work um or not like but like
see where the token was was used found
the endpoint I confirmed that it did
work I could take over that admin
accounts I mean that admin account um
and I can also switch that the header
that was leaked with another ID another
user so I could take any any um account
over from that from my own tenant but
remember that tenant ID that I
earlier those IDs are um mongod DB IDs o
innumerable so they're not yeah so it's
possible to change the
tenant uh remove uh so like change the
tenant ID remove the um the user ID in
the header so that you have access to
only like the tenant data and and there
is one end point in particular where
it's listed the user and user IDs it so
so in the end I could take over as an
exal user from tenant a I could take
over any user accounts from tenant b c d
e oh my god dude so that's clutch so
clarifying question there where where
was the JWT leak did you say it was in a
header uh in the response uh in the air
Message In the response so so was that
like you know but like was it just
saying hey there's an error by the way
here's the token you know like like uh
it Le like the whole hcp request so had
like some sort of reverse proxy was
going on
there very interesting so like the the
headers um cookies there were none uh C
surf token as well but it was like set
to nothing sort to nothing as well as so
the headers did had the JW authorization
be then the value then that specific
header with the tenant ID and the other
custom header with the user ID so by all
of that together uh as an ex user I
could take over any account on any other
tenant dang dude you love it you love to
see it that that whenever you get a nice
verbose air that helps so much you can
you can really you can really infer so
many things about the application by
using those a lot of the time and even
if even if um you know even if it
doesn't contain a bunch of information
do a based testing as well I've seen
fron do that at a live hacking event not
too long ago and just essentially using
his input in such a way that it would
generate an error about something that
he couldn't see you know and and use
that to infer what kind of you know data
type this is or what kind of object this
is really really fun stuff there all
right last one ssti to rce anible
Expressions dude I'm excited hit me so
um do you remember you just spoke about
him in's talk on emails and like that uh
ever since this talk I've always been
putting um ssci payloads in my email for
example Jrock plus 7times s blah cooler
brackets blah blah blah and um it rarely
works it worked once but thought it was
like out of scope but in this case um it
did work so I put in my payload like in
my email as my registered user worked on
the app a couple of days um and it was
like an app where people could spin up
their own WordPress instances and they
would also get access to like a their
own PHP my admin console where they
could manage like the database what not
and after a few days I spent time just
looking at the tables and P on and uh
looked at the user table and noticed
that my email was Jrock plus 49 I was
like oh [__] my uh ssti payload worked
interesting but how and where
um few days later laterally spent
probably 8 to 12 hours on figure out
what engine was
used um I think I might have even asked
the developer uh from the program on the
previous report like what could this be
and they told me um yeah I think not
sure if I figur it myself or they told
me they probably told me that it was
anable so since you could spin up like
your own instances it did use anible to
like configure all of that interesting
and in the end my input was being
um I mean the sync was in an anable conf
F in a Playbook to be more specific way
so I could use I could leak leak anible
variables um for example like remember
just like as my as my original PC I
leaked like the anable config file I
could like the current user like that
wow um and then later on I I was like I
can leak stuff what if I can actually do
stuff um so looking at the anable dogs I
found the um anable lookup command so if
you do like lookup um and then like in
parenthesis pipe comma follow by the
command it'll actually execute that
execute the
command yeah uh there were a few
restrictions on on characters though so
I could not put um all characters I just
had to hex and code them actually uh so
I actually downloaded anible created my
own Playbook and tested to see how it
worked and it turns out that um URL
encoded characters did not work I mean
they work locally but not on the
application but by hex encoding the
characters that were blocked on the
application um it still worked unable
locally uh so yeah it just led to uh
lots of reading and and researching to
finally NRC which was pretty
that's awesome so this is what you know
you have it as called ssti here um and
and surely it is but also it's kind of
like configuration file injection as
well right right I'm I'm I'm wondering
if yeah because configuration file
injection is something we kind of talked
about a couple times on the Pod
specifically surrounding some live
hacking events that we were working on
um and it's such an interesting it's
such an interesting vulnerability type
and there so it really does make you
dive deep in reading the docs to
actually figure out how to fully exploit
it because then you've got to become a
master of this you know this arbitrary
tool that you've never used and you've
got to figure out you know hey can I use
hex encoding inside of this config file
and like that sort of thing so it's
definitely expands your mind a bit as a
hacker to do those sort of uh those sort
of Vols I think I called it ssti because
uh when I originally reported it I can
only leak data I could not get an RC I
was like this is probably just like a
some kind of engine where it was weird
um I think before even I found out that
it was anible so to me it's was like
it's evaluating my 7times 7 it must be
some kind of suicide templ engine that
is evaluating that and at the end like
you said it's not really uh an ass I
mean yeah I won't say it's like conf
injection to in is not what what I you
know you're going through like is it
Ginga no is it is it twig anible
ispr I mean anible uh the expressions
are based on ging are they okay so
originally when I found out I tried the
typical payow and that they not work uh
but found out that lookup uh I mean
lookup is actually a plugin but it's in
Saw by default um so with the lookup
plugin you can just do pipe and I mean
the little string pipe in the in
parenthesis and then ex come wow that's
that's awesome that's a good that's a
good takeway you know if you're really
really stumped on an ssti or something
that looks like an ssti think maybe hey
there could be some surrounding
functionality that's using a templating
engine that you're actually injecting
into that's that's a that's something
that's a possibility that I've never
considered before the same thing
happened with terraform really actually
I had a case where I could leak
terraform variables uh but nothing more
not terraform I didn't dive too much in
it since it was on aent so I didn't want
to spend too much time on it uh but it
has happened in the past where um I
could inject I guess strings or whatnot
in a terraform from Pig Dude very cool
man there is there is potential with
like everything uh infrastructure as Cod
related and you know um St tools like
that whenever there's there's these um
applications that do things like spin up
uh other services and stuff like that
even the most advanced stuff I find is
duct tape together you know like
somewhere somebody's shelling out you
know or some somewhere someone is like
dynamically generating a config file and
then you know having it loaded into this
service so um those are the places where
it it really pays to dive deep and
really understand hey especially if you
have code you know it really helps if
you have code um you know to understand
where those sort of um uh sort of
delimiters where those um the line
between one environment starts in one
starts and and ends uh there's so many
there's so many vs to be found in that
in that area um that's true dude awesome
bugs thank you so much for coming on and
sharing all of these this is probably
you know you've shared a ton of V
stories uh and lots of lots of cool tips
and tricks in there so thanks for being
so open with that and sharing your your
hacking success yeah up to you Lu with
this morning yeah absolutely all right
man have a good one thanks to the that
is the Pod bye
[Music]